Ruth Bernstein Papers, 1945 - 1949
Smith College Archives
Ruth Bernstein Papers
1945 - 1949
Bernstein, Ruth (Class of 1949)
80
1 box (.5 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
Alumna. Contains correspondence, class notes and pamphlets.
Biographical Note
Please contact the College Archives for Ruth Bernstein's biographical information.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
This collection contains correspondence written by Ruth "Babs" Bernstein to her parents and sister "Mar". A dedicated correspondent, the collection contains daily and weekly letters from the entirety of her first year through her junior year at Smith College. The collection also contains a few letters received during her time at Smith College as well as a number of pamphlets, flyers, and class notes from 1945 - 1949.
Organization of the Collection
This collection is organized into two series:
Correspondence Sent
Correspondence Received
APPENDIX: subject index
This guide to topics found within this collection was prepared by Hilary Buxton.
Amherst College 10/17/1945
10/29/1945
11/11/1945
4/21/1946
3/15/1948
Social Life 11/7/1945
11/24/1945
3/18/1946
4/28/1946
5/6/1946
5/16/1946
College Curriculum 5/16/1946
4/17/1947
4/21/1947
Arts, Drama, and Music 10/25/1945
12/6/1945
12/17/1945
11/12/1946
1/21/1946
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives except where noted in the finding aid.
The Ruth Bernstein Papers, 1945 - 1949 were created by Ruth Bernstein and donated to the College Archives at the Class of 1949's 50th reunion in May, 2009.
correspondence; Smith College -- Students; Smith College -- Social life and customs -- Sources; Smith College -- Alumni and alumnae -- History -- Sources
The following related materials are available in the Smith College Archives:
Class of 1949 Records, 1945-[ongoing]
- Series I: Correspondence Sent
  - September - October, 1945 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - November - December, 1945 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - January - February, 1946 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - March - April, 1946 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - May - June, 1946 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - December, 1946 - April, 1947 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - May - June, 1947 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - September - October, 1947 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - November - December, 1947 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - January - February, 1948 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - March - April, 1948 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: Correspondence Received
  - December, 1945 - February, 1946 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - miscellaneous 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - class notes 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)